hey guys this looks like a fun one we're
trying to find X the area of this red
region if you want to try it on your own
pause it right now cuz I'm going to
solve it in 3 2 1 Let's copy it down and
let's focus on this left semicircle
let's cut it in half and split this into
five and five and then let's focus on
this top semicircle and cut it in half
and make this five and five so now we've
split our white region up into these
three pieces this one right here is a
square of 5 * 5 which means the area is
25 and this blue portion right here was
half of the semicircle or in other words
a quarter Circle the area of the quarter
circle is PK r^ 2 / 4 and the radius of
this quarter circle is equal to 5 so we
can plug in five for the r and 5^ s is
equal to 25 so the area of the blue
region is 25 pi over4 and this quarter
Circle right here is the exact same so
it's also 25 pi over4 and now we know
the area of our white region we can just
add these three things together and 25i
4 + 25i 4 4 would be 50 piun 4 we can
simplify this to 25 piun / 2 this is the
area of our white region and if we add X
to this that'll give us the area of the
entire Square which is 10x 10 or 100 now
we just got to solve for x we can
subtract 25 from both sides these two
will cancel each other out and 100 minus
25 is 75 then we can subtract 25 pi over
2 from both sides on the left hand side
these will cancel out and on the right
hand side we'll have 75 - 25 pi over 2
and that's the answer to our question
let's give it a label of square units
and put a box around it and the
approximate value of this is 35.7 3
square units how exciting